(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
今日も大天才っ！
Today is also a great genius!
だーいてんさいっ！
Great genius!
(大優勝 中毒 重症)
(Big victory, Addiction, Serious condition)
今日も大天才っ！
Today is also a great genius!
だーいてんさいっ！
Great genius!
あ〜 ずっともっと 推し事させてっ
Ah~ forever more, let me do the work of a fan!
ね？
Okay?
今日は莉々華の生誕祭ライブ！
Today is Ririka's Birthday Celebration Live!
見に来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to see me!
たくさんのゲストと プロジェクトいっぱい歌うからね！
I'll be singing a lot from the project with many guests!
盛り上がっていこー！
Let's get hyped up!
アクスタ 痛バ ぬい 準備万端！
Acrylic stands, itabag, plushies, all ready!
オシャレも気合入れちゃって
Getting all dressed up and fired up,
誰の為なの〜？
Who is it for...?
狙うことなき推しの為です！
It's for my oshi, without a doubt!
古参 新参も 人権は平等
Old fans, new fans, everyone's equal here.
内に秘めた古参マウント
An old-fan flex hidden deep inside...
Not 同担拒否ですが
I don't reject fans of the same oshi, but...
すごーし嫉妬はするかも…
I might get a little bit jealous...
いいねボタン足りません…
The like button isn't enough...
これ無料でいいんですか？
Is it really okay to watch this for free?
日々好きが募る
My love grows every day,
尊すぎるでしょ… 困っちゃうなぁ
you're too precious... It's troublesome.
今日も大天才っ！
Today is also a great genius!
だーいてんさいっ！
Great genius!
推し出し惜しみ無理絶対 考えたくもないなぁ
Holding back my support? Absolutely impossible, can't even imagine it.
生き甲斐
My reason for living!
お仕事は年中無休です
Work is 24/7, 365 days a year.
もう大天才っ！
I'm already a great genius!
あ〜限界！これ以上キュンキュンされたら
Ah, my limit! If you make my heart throb any more...
困ります
I'll be in trouble.
だって召されたい
Because I want to go to heaven from joy.
絶対免罪！
Absolute exoneration!
あなたが一番です！
You are number one!
予約した推しのフィギュア
The figure of my favorite I pre-ordered...
来年発送予定 (マジ！？)
is scheduled to ship next year (Seriously!?)
え〜そんなの慣れっこです
Eh, I'm used to that.
忘れた頃に来るけど…！
It'll arrive when I've forgotten about it...!
溢れる才能 無量大数
Overflowing talent, infinity...
ですが、
But...
セル画のままに増えすぎる らびゅー！
Increasing just like cels, love you!
あ〜もう好き！
Ah, I love you so much!
今日も大天才っ！ だーいてんさいっ！
A great genius today too! G-g-genius!
死ぬ無理待っててぇ 考えられないや…
Dying, no way, wait! I can't think...
尊い
Precious.
次の現場まで待てないや
I can't wait until the next live.
もう大天才っ！ あ〜限界！
Already a great genius! Ah, my limit!
切り詰めた生活 何一つ苦じゃない
Life on a tight budget isn't hard at all.
だってこんなにも
Because even like this...
幸せ溢れた日々です
it's a day overflowing with happiness.
今日も
Today too.
あなたと！
With you!
わたしで！
With me!
ビッグバンしたいの！
I want to Big Bang!
愛は地球くらいに膨らんでこんなになってんぞ
Love swells to the size of Earth and becomes like this
支え合えた惑星はこのときのためにスタート！
The planets that supported each other start for this moment!
Ring-dong, ring-dong
鼓動が Beat it
The heartbeat is beating it
期待も Heat up
Expectations also heat up
感じて Joy-joy! もっとハッピー!
Feel it Joy-joy! More happy!
Joy-joy! もっとエンジョイ!
Joy-joy! More enjoy!
フィジカル・スイミング
Physical Swimming
絶好調キブン もっと強つよホームラン
In peak condition, a more strong-strong home run
爆勝シンの才能ヒエラルキー
Hierarchy of victory's talent
ワン・ツー・スリー 見せてあげる ラブリー・パーティー
One, two, three, I'll show you, Lovely Party
ドゥルン・ドゥ・ドゥルン・ドゥ 巻き起こる小手先ダイタイフーン
Drun-du-drun-du... A small-scale big typhoon brewing
もっとハッピー! とことん! とことん! とどけちゃうよ!
More happy! Thoroughly! Thoroughly! I'll deliver it!
そうだろう? こうだろう? ときめきだろう?
Isn't it so? Is it like this? Isn't it excitement?
La-la-love いかがですか?
La-la-love, how is it?
ちょっとビビッと感じたなら
If you felt a little spark
止めらんない 止めどないくらい 胸のドキドキ ドキ!
I can't stop, my heart is pounding so much it won't end!
一周回って現在進行 ぐるぐる追いかけっこ
Going around once, currently in progress, round and round playing tag
あらららあらモード
Oh-oh-oh-oh-a-la-mode
このままいくよ
I'm going like this
Ring-dong, ring-dong
鼓動が Beat it
The heartbeat is beating it
期待も Heat up
Expectations also heat up
もっと感じて
Feel it more
Jumping jumping ディスプレイを Jamming
Jumping jumping, jamming the display
お作法気分 新世代タイム
Manner feeling, new generation time
異論反論は認めません
Objections and rebuttals are not allowed
史上最高のコトバマジスター
The greatest word magister in history
You and I ここから Ready!
You and I, ready from here!
ずっと見ててね
Keep watching me
リリカルMonster シュプリーム!
Lyrical Monster, Supreme!
増すするかの 勢いブーンブーン
Will it increase? Momentum boom-boom
もっと騒げ Put your hands ブーンブーン
Make more noise, Put your hands boom-boom
ラーだけじゃないの! ときめき! ほめて!
It's not just "la"! Excitement! Praise me!
伸びて絶頂天
Growing to the peak of heaven
Aban-ban, aban-ban, テンパれば脳内タイフーン
Aban-ban... if I panic, a typhoon in my brain
やっぱクレイジー バシバシバシバシ 鍛えちゃうよ!
After all, it's crazy! I'll train you hard!
Give me a love, give me a love, 揺るがぬLoveがオールオーバー!
Give me a love... unshakable love all over!
いかがですか?
How is it?
もっと明快感じてよ
Feel it more clearly
やめらんない 目が離せない 君のハッシュタグ #箱!
I can't stop, I can't take my eyes off your hashtag #Hako!
もう一回回って通常運転 のびのびいつも通り
Going around once more, normal operation, relaxed as usual
あらららあらかると
Oh-oh-oh-oh-a-la-carte
このままいくよ
I'm going like this
Ring-dong, ring-dong 強速は不穏
Ring-dong, ring-dong, high speed is unsettling
想像以上の正体するから
Because I'll reveal a true identity beyond imagination
Bumpy bumpy 期待したもんに?
Bumpy bumpy... to what was expected?
度表しない発見もご愛嬌
Unexpected discoveries are also charming
朗読な中じゃありません
It's not just reading aloud
空前絶後のコトバマジシャン
Unprecedented word magician
Yes oh yes なんでもオーライ!
Yes oh yes, anything is alright!
一緒にSinging リリカルなStar! Amazing!
Singing together, Lyrical Star! Amazing!
本当はね、リリカちゃんと二人で歌って踊ってみたいって思ってたんだけどね。
Actually, I was thinking I wanted to sing and dance together with Ririka-chan.
まさかこんな形で叶うなんて。
I never thought it would come true in this way.
誰が一番驚いてるって、団長だかんね！
If anyone is most surprised, it's the Commander!
ピントが違う時もあるよ
There are times when the focus is different
そこがいいところ
That's the good part
どんな日も笑顔にする 確信
Conviction to make every day a smile
どんどんワクワク 相乗効果!
More and more exciting, synergy effect!
ニコニコ 100万点! あらららラブアピール!
Smiles, 1 million points! Oh-oh-oh-oh-love appeal!
このままいくよ
I'm going like this
まだまだいくよ
Still going
ついてきてよね
Follow me, okay?
Ring-dong, ring-dong みんななら
Ring-dong, ring-dong, if it's all of you
Ring-dong, ring-dong できるはずさ
Ring-dong, ring-dong, you should be able to do it
Ring-dong, ring-dong 聴かせて
Ring-dong, ring-dong, let me hear it
Ring-dong, ring-dong 大きな声で
Ring-dong, ring-dong, in a loud voice
Ring-dong, ring-dong 鼓動が Beat it
Ring-dong, ring-dong, the heartbeat is beating it
期待も Heat up
Expectations also heat up
もっと感じて
Feel it more
Jumping jumping ディスプレイを Jamming
Jumping jumping, jamming the display
いつもあなたのハッピーで在ろう
Let's always be your happiness
異論反論は認めません
Objections and rebuttals are not allowed
史上最高のリリの笑顔から
From Riri's greatest smile ever
ますますラビング 一緒にシンギング
More and more loving, singing together
リリカルなStar! Amazing!
Lyrical Star! Amazing!
リリカルMonster シュプリーム! Yeaaah!
Lyrical Monster, Supreme! Yeaaah!
跪きなさい！
Kneel!
汝、この城の扉を叩いたものよ。
You, who have knocked on the doors of this castle!
誓いなさい。
Vow to me.
このルーナの盾となり、矛となり
To be this Luna's shield and spear,
夜はぐっすり眠れるまで
until you can sleep soundly at night...
ともに歩むことを！
to walk together!
捧げなさい、姫であると
Offer it up, for I am a princess
玉座の！
At the throne!
どなた 紅茶のカップをカチャカチャ鳴らさない、えらい！
Who's that clinking their teacup? Good job for not doing it!
スコーンだって零さず綺麗に食べて、すごい！
Eating your scones without making a mess, amazing!
たまに王冠どっちが前か間違っちゃうの、かわいい！
Mistaking which way the crown goes, how cute!
とっても よしなのな 解状！
Very good! Dismissed!
ルナナイト大合唱！
Luna Night grand chorus!
何よりルーナが好きな人！
Everyone who loves Luna above all else!
ルナナイト大合唱！
Luna Night grand chorus!
シルクの布団持ってきて！
Bring over the silk futon!
ルナナイト大合唱！
Luna Night grand chorus!
三時のお茶会来れる人！
Anyone who can come to the 3 PM tea party!
守れなかったら即制裁！
If you fail to protect me, immediate punishment!
分かってほしいのら…
I want you to understand...
これも帝王学を学ぶため…
this too, is to learn about monarchical studies...
愛という名の教育なのリラ！
It's an education called love!
守ってルナナイト
Protect me, Luna Night
奢ってルナナイト
Treat me, Luna Night
プロムナード ボイコット なのなのな
Boycotting the promenade, nano-nano-na
手の甲にチュッ
A kiss on the back of the hand
誓いへのチュッ
A kiss for the vow
ガラスの靴 履かせてわがまま
Selfishly making you put on the glass slipper
守ってルナナイト
Protect me, Luna Night
困ってルナナイト
Bother me, Luna Night
無性にキャンディねだりたくなってもね
Even if I suddenly feel like begging for candy
君がいなきゃ だってみんな
Because without you, everyone...
誇らしくて 捧げなさい 姫であると
would be so proud. Offer it up, for I am a princess
ルーナってお菓子のあと、ちゃんと歯磨きするの、えらい！
Luna always brushes her teeth after sweets, good girl!
目覚ましなくたって起きられちゃうの、すごい！
I can wake up without an alarm, amazing!
ステップ こんがらがっちゃったのも、かわいい！
Getting my steps all tangled up is cute, too!
今日の褒め言葉 よしなのな 解状！
Today's praise was good! Dismissed!
ルナナイト大合唱！
Luna Night grand chorus!
ルーナを本気にさせる人！
Everyone who makes Luna get serious!
ルナナイト大合唱！
Luna Night grand chorus!
ダイヤの花束 摘んできて！
Go pick a diamond bouquet!
ルナナイト大合唱！
Luna Night grand chorus!
ドラゴン ペットにできる人！
Anyone who can keep a dragon as a pet!
つべこべ言わずに即実行！
Don't complain, just do it!
きっと分かってくれるのら…
I'm sure you'll understand...
交渉論だって読んだのら…
I've even read about negotiation theory...
恋はいつだって試練なのら！
Love is always a trial!
守ってルナナイト
Protect me, Luna Night
踊ってルナナイト
Dance with me, Luna Night
オペラハウス 貸切 なのなのな
Renting out the opera house, nano-nano-na
跪いてチュッ
Kneel down for a kiss
制約誓いのチュッ
A kiss for the binding vow
ドレスのバラ 咲かせてランダム
Making roses bloom randomly on my dress
守ってルナナイト
Protect me, Luna Night
分かってルナナイト
Understand me, Luna Night
バルコニーで待つ月光にシュガー乗せちゃう
Waiting on the balcony to put sugar on the moonlight
あの子も綺麗だって そんな
Saying that other girl is pretty, too...
戯言はおやめなさい 姫であると
Cut out the nonsense. For I am a princess
守ってルナナイト
Protect me, Luna Night
想ってルナナイト
Think of me, Luna Night
プロムナード ボイコット なのなのな
Boycotting the promenade, nano-nano-na
永遠のチュッ
An eternal kiss
この指にチュッ
A kiss on this finger
ガラスの靴 履かせてわがまま
Selfishly making you put on the glass slipper
守ってルナナイト
Protect me, Luna Night
困ってルナナイト
Bother me, Luna Night
無性にキャンディねだりたくなってもね
Even if I suddenly feel like begging for candy
君がいなきゃ だってみんな
Because without you, everyone...
誇らしくて 捧げなさい 姫であると
would be so proud. Offer it up, for I am a princess
なのになんで？
So why is it?
親和性打ち込み 際立って 本日開廷
Affinity injection stands out, court is in session today
ざわボロ ぎゅむバキ 手にする全部
Shaking and broken, crushing and snapping, everything in hand
It's my プレープレー
It's my play-play
適当に頑張ろうぜ
Let's just give it our best haphazardly
そんなん待っていいけどさ
It's fine to wait for that, but...
必死に頑張ろうぜ
Let's try our hardest desperately
それが僕ららしいよな
That seems just like us, right?
逆さ過ぎじゃねんだわ
It's not that it's too upside down
そんで ぼっちじゃねんだわ
And I'm not all alone
うん！ 万事がバッチリ イケてる自分に 決まってる！
Yeah! Everything's perfect, I'm cool for sure!
Are you かなたちゃん？
Are you Kanata-chan?
怒涛前進 冗談 ちゃんと 感謝して
Surging forward, jokes aside, give proper thanks
パンダラダ 特選 毎食 騒動
Pandara-da, Special selection, every meal's a riot
ちゃんと 共鳴して
Resonate properly
どうしよう？
What should I do?
僕が言うんだもん
Because I'm the one saying it
本当にするんだもん
Because I'm really gonna do it!
現実超えろ未来 Ah
Exceed reality, future! Ah...
弱点も平気 スイッチでランチャー
Weaknesses are fine, switch on the launcher!
すなわち特者生存ワンダランダディ
In other words, Survival of the Fittest Wanda-randa Day!
楽しもう
Let's have some fun!
面白がれること探し給え オーバー
Go find something to enjoy! Over!
返事聞かせてくれ
Let me hear your answer!
右左どっちじゃない
It's not about left or right,
決めつけていい属性
attributes you can decide for yourself!
ちなみたくなったら発射
If you want to try it, fire it off!
ライダー！ワクワクするぜーション
Rider! It's a thrilling-ation!
聞いて 推し被りちゃー！アイドルの子楽しい
Listen! Oshikaburi-cha! Being an idol is fun,
でもガチ恋結婚は立ち直ってません
but I haven't recovered from 'Gachikoi' marriage!
七色の出るまで回せ 100％ピックアップ
Spin until it shines! 100% Rate Up!
あ、天井です
Ah, I hit the pity...
なんだよそんなこと言っちゃダメだおバカ
Hey, you shouldn't say that, dummy!
賢い ありがとう
Smart! Thank you!
日々是三全泥五マイウェイ
Every day is my way!
星探していたいんだもん
Because I want to keep searching for stars!
だって息ガンガンがいいんだもん
Because I want to feel fully alive!
全方位にガッツリアンテナ張ってなくちゃ
Gotta keep my antenna out in all directions!
いつでも心はちゃんと純粋で
Keeping my heart pure at all times,
イタイな好奇心は絶えず熱心で
my painful curiosity is always eager.
痛いって言い聞かせるの
I tell myself it hurts,
調子に乗ったらすぐ飽きられちゃうから
because if I get cocky, people will get bored!
Ah 最高なロボどどんとこいで
Ah, bring on the best robot!
すなわち特者生存ワンダランダディ
That is, Survival of the Fittest Wanda-randa Day!
進化見つけ
Find your evolution!
努力とは最後まで諦めないこと
Effort means never giving up until the end!
メモっておいて
Take a note of that!
本当はベイビー 自信なんかないよ
Truth is, baby, I have no confidence!
本当はベイビー 不安ばかりで泣きそう
Truth is, baby, I'm so anxious I could cry!
でもねベイビー 挫けないって決めたの
But you see, baby, I've decided not to break!
だからベイビー 挑戦したいよ 未開の地 無限のフィールドで
So baby, I want to challenge the unknown...
前進ちゃんと自覚して
Aware of my progress,
高まり行く想像ちゃんと共有して
sharing this rising imagination,
興奮しよう
let's get excited!
僕が言うんだもん 本当にするんだもん
Because I'm the one saying it! I'm really gonna do it!
現実超えろ未来 Ah
Exceed reality, future! Ah...
弱点も平気スイッチでランチャー
Weaknesses are fine, switch on the launcher!
すなわち特者生存ワンダランダディ
In other words, Survival of the Fittest Wanda-randa Day!
楽しもう
Let's enjoy it!
面白がれること探し放題だぜ
Searching for fun is all you can do!
無限のフィールドで
In the infinite field!
パニングしなくてもいいかな
Maybe I don't need to pan around?
どんな暗い調整
No matter how dark the adjustment,
ちなみこれが僕の答えなんだ
by the way, this is my answer!
胸を張れ 今を生きるその意味を
Stand tall, and the meaning of living for now,
飽くる日も飽くる日も確かめ進め
confirm it day after day as you move forward!
わー！できたー！
Wah! We did it!
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much! Thank you!
一条莉々華生誕祭ライブ2025にお越しくださりありがとうございます！
Thank you for coming to Ichijou Ririka Birthday Festival Live 2025!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
今日なんともう一人ね 来てもらってるのでMCを呼びたいと思います！
Today, we actually have one more guest, so let's call the MC!
こより先輩！
Koyori-senpai!
イェーイ！リリたん誕生日おめでとう！
Yay! Happy Birthday, Riri-tan!
ありがとうございます！嬉しいー！
Thank you so much! I'm so happy!
早速自己紹介させていただいてもよろしいでしょうか？
May I introduce myself right away?
本日の主役、可愛いポジティブ・ジーニアスの一条莉々華だよ！
Today's star, the cute Positive Genius, Ichijou Ririka!
大人になりました。
I've grown into an adult.
握力50kg ギチギチ 握り潰すぞ！かなたんこと天音かなたです！
Grip strength 50kg! Gichi-gichi! I'll crush you! I'm Amane Kanata!
みんなこんこよー！ホロライブの頭脳、ジーニアス博衣こよりだよー！
Kon-koyo everyone! The brain of Hololive, Genius Hakui Koyori!
またジーニアスが一人増えた！奪われちゃう！
Another genius joined! She's gonna steal my title!
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
待って、なんか変な動きしてへん？もしかして
Wait, are you doing a weird movement? Maybe?
みんな面白いから、これやって！
Everyone, it's funny, so do this!
両方にいるからね！両方見たいんだけど！
I'm on both sides! I want to see both though!
ありがとう、ありがとう！莉々華は、ありがとうございます！
Thank you, thank you! Ririka... thank you so much!
早速ですねライブスタートしたわけなんですが
The live show has started right away...
今回の配信のハッシュタグ！右上のこちら！
The hashtag for this stream! This one on the top right!
こちら！こちら！ハッシュタグ #一条莉々華生誕祭2025 となってます！
This one! This one! The hashtag is #IchijouRirikaBirthday2025!
Xでたくさんたくさんポストしてくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you post a lot on X!
スクショとか感想とか、モリモリ待ってます！
I'm waiting for lots of screenshots and thoughts!
かなた先輩と「特者生存ワンダラダー」歌わせていただきました！
I sang "Tokusha Seizou Wonderer" with Kanata-senpai!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
でもこの曲本当に可愛くて、もう踊りもめっちゃ可愛いし！
But this song is really cute, and the dance is so cute too!
嬉しい！ありがとう！めちゃくちゃ歌えて踊れて嬉しかったです！
I'm happy! Thank you! I was so happy to sing and dance!
私こそ莉々華の声でね、聴けて踊ってもらえて本当に幸せでした！ありがとう！
Me too, hearing Ririka's voice and dancing with her, I was so happy!
ありがとうございます！やったー！
Thank you so much! Yay!
そして、このあとね、こよりちゃん先輩はあの曲を…
And after this, Koyori-chan senpai will sing THAT song...!
歌わせていただきます！
I'll be singing it!
どの曲なんだろう！あれかな！あれかな！
I wonder which song it is! Is it that one? Or that one?
もう莉々華の大好きな曲で本当に…！
It's a song Ririka loves so much, really...!
あれ？なんかちょっとおかしいぞ？
Wait? Something is a bit strange?
なんだこれ！赤いよ！
What is this! It's red!
へ？へ？大丈夫か？なんか出てくるぞ！
Huh? Huh? Is it okay? Something is coming out!
なんだ！なんだ！ちょっとどうなってんだよ莉々華！
What! What! Hey, what's going on, Ririka?!
わからない！本当に！
I don't know! Really!
でも待ってください！あそこにゾンビ撃退クリームがある！
But wait! There's zombie repellent cream over there!
なんやそれ！取りに行きましょう！
What's that! Let's go get it!
ソフトクリームだよね…
It's probably soft-serve ice cream...
違います！これは幻のクリームですよ！
No! This is the legendary cream!
説明役どこ貸してんだよ！
Where are you getting this narrator role from?!
これをゾンビに当てれば、多分ゾンビを…
If we hit the zombies with this, we should be able to...
殲滅できるはず！
annihilate the zombies!
多分？！できなかったら死んで！
Probably?! If we can't, we're dead!
やばいやばい！行け行け！莉々華、見ろよ！
Oh no! Go go! Ririka, watch!
見てろ、やり方を！
Watch how it's done!
物理なんだ…
It's physical...
やったぜー！なんとかなりました！
We did it! We managed somehow!
危ない危ない！なんか一瞬かっこつけてたけどな！
Dangerous! Though you looked cool for a second!
変だよ！乗っ取りは完了ということ！
That's weird! The takeover is complete!
乗っ取られてんの？ゾンビに…大丈夫？離せよ！
Are you being taken over? By the zombies? Are you okay? Speak up!
大丈夫です！離せよ！乗っ取ったんだよ！
I'm okay! Speak up! I took over!
あ、戻った！帰ってきてくれた！よかったー！
Ah, it's back! You came back! Thank God!
なんなんだこの…全くわからなかったぞ！一体何だったんだよ莉々華！
What was this... I didn't get it at all! What on earth was that, Ririka?!
実はですね…ちょっとお化け屋敷感みたいなのを
Actually... I wanted you to experience a bit of a haunted house vibe,
せっかく遊園地だから味わってほしいなって思って！
since we're at an amusement park!
えー？！待って！ジェットコースターがよかった！作謀だよ！
Wha?! Wait! I wanted the roller coaster! It's a plot!
スモークは焚いてほしいって言ったんですけど…
I did ask them to use smoke...
ちょっとまさかゾンビまで出てくるとは思わなくて！
I just didn't expect zombies to show up too!
怖すぎるだろ！あんたの説明口調のやつおかしかったぞ！
That's too scary! Your explanation was weird!
接待でしょだけだったよね！接待でしょだけだったよね！
It was just 'hospitality', wasn't it?! It was just 'hospitality'!
やばい！バレる！ま…ソフトクリームだ！
Oh no! I'm caught! I mean... soft-serve ice cream!
このあとはこよりちゃん先輩と歌わせて…
After this, I'll sing with Koyori-chan senpai...
この状態で？！どの心境でやればいいんだよ！
In this state?! What kind of mindset should I have for this!
晴れましたすみませんね！
It's cleared up, sorry about that!
かなた先輩、このあともちょっとここの遊園地で
Kanata-senpai, please relax at this amusement park
まったりゆっくりしててくださいな！
and take it easy for a bit!
ベンチで楽しんでて！
Enjoy yourself on the bench!
莉々華たちは行ってきます！二人で歌うぞ！
We're off! We're gonna sing together!
嘘でしょ？！ま…ま…ま…
You're kidding?! Ma... ma... ma...
え、ひとりぼっち？僕ひとりにさせられてんだけど！
Eh, all alone? I'm being left all by myself!
もうきみの心 チクっとしちゃえ
Let's prick your heart a little bit.
わおーん！
Waooon!
こより先輩、来てくれてありがとうございます！
Koyori-senpai, thank you so much for coming!
こちらこそ！わお！わお！
My pleasure! Wao! Wao!
「絶対無理」思っちゃうし だって だって 不安になるし
"It's absolutely impossible," I think, because I get anxious.
全然嘘つけないし
I can't tell lies at all.
「絶対無理」思っちゃうし だって だって わかまっすぐでし
"It's absolutely impossible," I think, because I'm so straightforward!
目指すキラキラの きっと僕次第だ
The sparkling future I aim for surely depends on me.
ビターギブアップなんて 言わないんだから
Because I'm not going to say "bitter give up"!
じっとしてらんないし だって だって 動いちゃう足
I can't stay still, because my legs just keep on moving!
ワンワンステップちゃん ちょっとずつ進めば 夢の色溶けちゃうな
Woof woof, step by step, if I move forward, the colors of my dream will blend!
なりたい僕を 君が好きな僕を ちゃんと余りなく見せたいな
I want to show you the me I want to be, the me you like, without leaving anything out!
あっちゃちゃ びっくりするほどできないじゃん
Ah-cha-cha, I'm surprisingly bad at this, aren't I?
間違って悩んだりばかりじゃん
I'm always making mistakes and worrying.
けど君に…
But if I...
見つけてほしくて
I wanted you to find me
僕は君を迎えに行くんだ
So I'm coming to pick you up
出会えたならハッピー
If we can meet, I'll be happy
WAO!!
叫んじゃえ
Just shout it out!
泣いて泣いて愛して尻尾振って
Crying, crying, loving, and wagging my tail
WAO!!
叫んじゃえ
Just shout it out!
舐めな僕をどうか覚えておいて
Please remember me, even if you look down on me
もうきみの心チクっとしちゃえ
I'll make your heart sting a little bit
もうどうしようとか
Sometimes I wonder what to do...
たまに思っちゃって沈んだり
...and get depressed
あーだいじょぶかも
Ah, maybe I'm okay?
ふらり感じちゃってまたダウナー
I feel dizzy and down again
べったりがやめられない
I can't stop being so clingy
おすわりってそれなんだっけ？
Sit stay? What was that again?
うっかりが止められない
I can't stop my carelessness
また踏んで僕に当たるの
You step on me and take it out on me again
わんわんステップアップ 死んだふりしてるの
Wan wan step up, I'm playing dead
やめて はいこっちおいで
Stop it, now come over here
欲しがる君と上げすぎな僕とで
With you wanting more and me giving too much
もっといける気がしています
I feel like we can go further
あっ ちゃっ ちゃ びっくりするほどできないじゃん
At-chat-cha, you can't do it at all, it's surprising
間違って悩んだりばっかりじゃ
If all you do is worry about mistakes...
手助け
A helping hand...
見つけてほしくて
...I wanted you to find me
僕は君を迎えに行くんだ 出会えたならハッピー
So I'm coming to pick you up, we'll be happy
だってやっぱりひとりじゃダメだけど
Because after all, being alone is no good
集まって馬鹿してわおっちゃえば
But if we get together, act silly, and go 'WAO!!'
ほら いつでも言える「おかえり」
See? We can always say 'Welcome home'
僕は君に伝えたいんだ大いなるハッピー
I want to convey a great happiness to you
WAO!!
叫んじゃえ
Just shout it out!
泣いて泣いて愛して尻尾振って
Crying, crying, loving, and wagging my tail
WAO!!
叫んじゃえ
Just shout it out!
舐めな僕をどうか覚えておいて
Please remember me, even if you look down on me
目指すキラキラもきっと僕次第だ
The sparkle I'm aiming for surely depends on me too
ビター？ギブアップなんて言わないんだから
Bitter? I'm not gonna say I give up
メラメラでぶちギレしなーいで
Don't get all flared up and blow your fuse
はぐれずに希望へ大爆走
Let's sprint towards hope without getting lost
きみの心チクっとしちゃっていいじゃんハッピーちゃん
It's fine to make your heart sting, Happy-chan
常世の闇に
In the eternal darkness...
囚われたまま
...trapped as you are,
奏でる悲鳴を
let me hear the screams...
聴かせて
...you play out.
さあ 爪を磨いたら
Now, once I've polished my claws,
まだ子供のようなあなたのために
it's for you, who's still like a child.
ああ 試されたいなら
Ah, if you want to be tested,
その愚かな手に手錠をかけて
then put handcuffs on those foolish hands.
常世の闇に 囚われたまま
Trapped in the eternal darkness,
甘い甘いガムを噛んでた
I was chewing sweet, sweet gum.
いくつもの後悔を
Offer up...
捧げて
...your many regrets.
さりげない合図に隠れて
Hidden in a casual signal,
答えはすぐにわからせてあげる
I'll make you understand the answer soon.
卑怯な嘘にまみれた
Covered in cowardly lies,
拒んだままに受け止めてあげる
I'll accept you as you refuse me.
ほら 悲鳴を 聴かせて
Now, let me hear your screams.
さあ 指を鳴らしたら
Now, once I've snapped my fingers,
この子猫のような私のために
it's for me, who's like this kitten.
ああ 喉が渇いたわ
Ah, I've grown thirsty,
紅色の口に指を散らして
scattering my fingers on your crimson mouth.
狭い部屋に閉じ込めたまま
Locked away in a small room,
首輪に繋がれたいの
I want to be chained to a collar.
くだらないルールじゃ奪えない
Foolish rules can't take it away,
自由はすでにこの手の中にある
freedom is already here in my hands.
愛情では測れない
It can't be measured by affection,
弱ったままに選ばせてあげる
I'll let you choose while you're weakened.
ほら 心を開いて
Now, open up your heart.
わからないフリをして
Pretaining not to know,
寝惚けてるの？
are you half-asleep?
もっと熱い暗闇見せて
Show me a deeper darkness,
ねえ
hey.
さりげない合図に隠れて
Hidden in a casual signal,
答えはすぐにわからせてあげる
I'll make you understand the answer soon.
卑怯な嘘にまみれた
Covered in cowardly lies,
拒んだままに受け止めてあげる
I'll accept you as you refuse me.
常世の闇に刻むその名を
The name carved into the eternal darkness...
わからせてあげる
...I'll make you understand it.
ほら 悲鳴を
Now, the screams...
聴かせてよ
...let me hear them.
夢見ないで
Don't you dream.
ほら 聴かせて
Now, let me hear you.
四六時中 帰りの会で
All day long, during the homeroom meeting,
面倒くささを押し付けられている
I'm burdened with all this annoyance.
何から何まで 私語は止めて
From start to finish, stop the private chatter.
まとめ役なら
If I'm the one in charge...
聞くを上手にうなずきあっている
I'll nod skillfully while listening.
なかよしこよしで
We're like best friends,
さあ だまれ だまりたまえよ
so come on, shut up, be quiet.
言えないねそんな強い言葉は
I can't say such strong words.
少しだけ静かにしてほしいな
I want you to be quiet for just a little while.
ああ 私たち待望へ
Ah, we are waiting for our future.
世界征服 ヤーヤーヤーヤー
World conquest, ya ya ya ya!
果たすすの日まで
Until the day it's fulfilled.
全人類 ヤーヤーヤーヤー
All of humanity, ya ya ya ya!
あなたの周りもよいよいよいよい
Even those around you, yoi yoi yoi yoi!
世界征服 アレアレヤー
World conquest, ale ale ya!
約束の地まで
Until the promised land.
さあ掲げよ バッテンバッテン
Now raise them, cross cross!
征服 ヤーヤーヤーヤー
Conquest, ya ya ya ya!
今日も議題 そっちのけだね
Today, you've set the agenda aside again.
嫌になるから 私一人でも
It's annoying, so even if I'm alone,
やっておきますね
I'll handle it myself.
すべて すべて すべて任せて
Everything, everything, leave it all to me.
それをさせてよ 大事なことなの
Let me do it, it's important.
わかっているでしょう
You understand, don't you?
四六時中 帰りの会で
All day long, during the homeroom meeting,
面倒くさいまま 今日も明日も過ぎて行くのでしょう
things stay annoying, today and tomorrow will pass like this.
花瓶に水をあげましょう
Let's water the vase.
時の中 しおれたこと忘れてた
In time, I forgot that it had withered.
さあ だだだだ まれだまりたまえよ
Come on, shut-sh-sh-shut up, be quiet.
言えないねそんな強い言葉は
I can't say such strong words.
少しだけ静かにしてほしいな
I want you to be quiet for just a little while.
ああ 私たち待望へ
Ah, we are waiting for our future.
今と未来 見たかったはずなのに
Even though I should have wanted to see now and the future.
世界征服 ヤーヤーヤーヤー
World conquest, ya ya ya ya!
見えるその日まで
Until the day I can see it.
三千世界 ヤーヤーヤーヤー
In all creation, ya ya ya ya!
これの理 よいよいよいよい
This is the way, yoi yoi yoi yoi!
今は征服 さあさあさあさあ
Now conquest, come on, come on, come on!
あなたの街中
Right in your town.
カタチヅクルわ バッテンさあ
I'll shape it with a cross.
世界征服 ヤーヤーヤーヤー
World conquest, ya ya ya ya!
果たすすの日まで
Until the day it's fulfilled.
全人類 ヤーヤーヤーヤー
All of humanity, ya ya ya ya!
あなたの周りもよいよいよいよい
Even those around you, yoi yoi yoi yoi!
世界征服 アレアレヤー
World conquest, ale ale ya!
約束の地まで
Until the promised land.
さあ掲げよ バッテンバッテン
Now raise them, cross cross!
征服したら ビンテージのワインを
Once conquered, let's open
空けましょう
a bottle of vintage wine.
おつめろー！ イェーイ！
Good job everyone! Yay!
はい！ということで、引き続きゲストパートお送りしておりましたが…
Yes! So, we've been bringing you the guest part...
なんと、もう一人MCに呼びたいと思います！
and I'd like to call one more person to the MC!
誰だ、誰だ、誰だ？
Who is it, who is it, who is it?
トワ先輩！ ハイ！ハイ！トワ様！ハイ！
Towa-senpai! Yes! Yes! Towa-sama! Yes!
イェーイ！ 来ていただいてありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you so much for coming!
いや、こちらこそ！
No, thank you!
ちょっとせっかくなんで自己紹介していただいてもいいですか？
Since you're here, could you introduce yourself?
はい！オッケー！ホロライブ4期生の、あれ…？
Yes! Okay! Of Hololive 4th Gen, wait...?
常闇トワです！ あれ、何だっけ？
I'm Tokoyami Towa! Wait, what was it again?
こんやっぴーがないから言えないんだ。こんやっぴー！
I can't say it without 'Konyappi'. Konyappi~!
はい、どうぞ！
Yes, go ahead!
はい、皆さん待たかね？
Yes, did everyone wait?
HoloXの女幹部、鷹嶺ルイと申します！
I am the HoloX female executive, Takane Lui!
リリカ、お誕生日おめでとう！ おめでとうございます！
Ririka, happy birthday! Happy birthday!
めっちゃ嬉しい！ 喜びの舞。
I'm so happy! A dance of joy.
いや、呼んでくれて嬉しいよ、お誕生日にさ。
I'm really happy you invited me for your birthday.
ありがとうございます！ もうルイ姉もトワ先輩も、
Thank you! Both Lui-nee and Towa-senpai...
もう凄くリリカに優しくしてくれる、リリカ的には姉御的な存在なので。
are so kind to me. To me, they're like big sisters.
まあまあまあ、慕ってくれて、慕ってくれて。 あ、そこは謙遜しないんだね。
Well, well, keep looking up to me. Oh, you're not humble about it.
前もな、前もトワのこと慕ったよな。 ああ、トワ、トワ、トワ。
Before, too, you looked up to Towa, didn't you? Ah, Towa, Towa, Towa.
本当に嬉しいです！
I'm truly happy!
やばい、このキラキラについていけない！ キラキラキラキラ…
Gosh, I can't keep up with this sparkles! Sparkle, sparkle...
一条莉々華の遊園地なんです！
It's Ririka Ichijou's amusement park!
めちゃ広い！いいじゃん！
It's so huge! Nice!
最高ですね。最高のステージですね。
It's the best. The best stage.
ジェットコースターもあるんだよ。
There's even a roller coaster.
見て見て！後で乗ろうよ。
Look, look! Let's ride it later.
色々あるんですね。凄！スピード凄！
There's so much. Wow! It's so fast!
ちゃんと乗れるようになってるんで、是非乗ってもらいたいんですよね。
It's actually rideable, so I really want you to ride it.
じゃあ後で一緒に乗ろうよ。
Then let's ride together later.
乗りたい、乗りたい！
I want to ride, I want to ride!
でも一旦、実は出店も用意してるので、良かったらこっちに来てください。
But first, I've prepared some stalls, so please come this way if you'd like.
出店！何食べれるのかな？
Stalls! I wonder what we can eat?
こっちです！こっち、こっち。
This way! This way, this way.
じゃん！出店もありますよ。
Ta-da! There are stalls too.
凄！ぽつんって今映る？
Amazing! Was that just standing there alone?
ぽつんじゃないですよ！
It's not alone!
バルーンも付いてるんだね。そうそう、凄！
There are balloons too. Right, right, amazing!
ちょっとこの出店でソフトクリーム食べれるんで、
At this stall, we can eat soft-serve ice cream,
莉々華が先輩たちに、いつもお世話になってる先輩たちにご馳走します！
so Ririka will treat you seniors who always take care of me!
やったー！奢りですか？
Yay! It's a treat?
もちろんです！流石社長だよ。
Of course! As expected of the president.
食べましょう、食べましょう。美味しそうだな。
Let's eat, let's eat. It looks delicious.
いただきまーす！
Thank you for the food!
イェーイ！もらったー。
Yay! I got it.
良かったら食べてください。いただきまーす。
Please eat. Thank you for the food.
ありがとう。うまいわ。
Thank you. It's good.
おいしーい！
Delicious!
Thank you! 甘い！
Thank you! It's sweet!
ね！めちゃくちゃ濃厚でうまいな。いいソフトクリーム。
Right! It's so rich and delicious. Good soft-serve.
ね、良くアイス食べる？
Right, do you eat ice cream often?
食べる。
I do.
食べる。アイス大好き。
I do. I love ice cream.
大好きですか？良かったー。
You love it? I'm glad.
私ミルクが好きなんよ。ミルクうまいよね。
I like milk flavor. Milk is good, isn't it?
え、トワ先輩は？
Wait, what about Towa-senpai?
え、私もね、このワッフルコーン大好きで、良く食べるよ。
I also love this waffle cone and eat it often.
ワッフルコーンいいよね。高級感あるわ。
Waffle cones are good. It feels high-class.
それはそう。ミルクがいいのよこれの。
That's true. The milk is good in this.
莉々華は実はあんまりアイス食べないんですけど、
Actually, Ririka doesn't eat ice cream that much,
食べないんだ！でもね、氷が好き！
You don't! But I like ice!
あー、氷ね。クリーム系だけど今日ね。
Ah, ice. But it's cream-type today.
しょうがないじゃん！
It can't be helped!
クリームしか在庫がなかったんだもん！
There was only cream in stock!
いえ、めちゃくちゃ旨いです。ありがとうございます。
No, it's really good. Thank you.
はい！ということで、じゃあちょっと今回のライブステージも紹介させてください。
Okay! So, let me introduce this time's live stage as well.
じゃじゃん！今回はなんと遊園地ステージとなっております！
Ta-da! This time, it's an amusement park stage!
すごーい！ロマンティック。
Amazing! Romantic.
夜空もすごい綺麗だし。綺麗でしょ？
The night sky is so beautiful too. It's beautiful, right?
凄くない？あ、ジェットコースターが今登って...
Isn't it amazing? Ah, the roller coaster is going up...
すげー！乗りてー！ジェットコースター速！
Awesome! I want to ride! The roller coaster is fast!
マジ速。行こうよ。
Really fast. Let's go.
ドキドキしちゃえないもしかしたら。
Maybe it'll make my heart race.
もう来るの？みたいな感じになってるね。
It's like "It's coming already?".
今？みたいなね。
Like "Now?".
ちょっと色々乗れるのもあるんで、良かったら先輩たちこの後もまったりしていってください。
There are various things you can ride, so please relax here after this too, seniors.
いいですか？うん！
Is it okay? Yeah!
え、じゃあ二人で乗って。ライブ見てるよ、こうやって食べながら。
Then let's ride together. I'll watch the live while eating.
映ったらごめんね、どこかに。
Sorry if you get caught on camera somewhere.
いるかもしれない、どこかに。探そう、探そう。
We might be somewhere. Let's look for us.
ね、もう本当に今日お二人に来て頂いてめちゃくちゃめちゃくちゃ嬉しくて。
Really, I'm so, so happy both of you came today.
まず一個目が、莉々華ね、トワ先輩の『FACT』一緒に歌わせて頂いたんですけど、
First, Ririka got to sing Towa-senpai's 'FACT' together,
デビューした直後に、ReGLOSSで同時視聴、トワ先輩のライブを同時視聴して...
right after debut, we at ReGLOSS did a watchalong of Towa-senpai's live...
そうだよな、そうだよな。
That's right, that's right.
その時にFACT聴いて、「やべー、めっちゃかっけー！莉々華もこんな風に歌えるようになりたい、踊れるようになりたい」って、
And then I heard FACT and thought "Whoa, so cool! I want to be able to sing and dance like that,"
こんな興奮してくれたんだ。
She was this excited.
マジです、これ！
I'm serious!
だから今回こうやって一緒にね、歌って踊ってもらって本当に嬉しいです。
So I'm really happy to have you sing and dance with me like this this time.
こちらこそ私一緒に出来て嬉しかったよ。ありがとうね。
Me too, I was happy to do it together. Thank you.
ありがとうございます。素敵でした。
Thank you very much. It was wonderful.
キアルンとは『OVERDOSE』歌って踊らせて頂きましたけど、めっちゃ嬉しい！
With Kiarun, I got to sing and dance 'OVERDOSE,' I'm so happy!
でもOVERDOSEもめちゃくちゃ好きな曲で！
But OVERDOSE is also a song I really love!
言ってくれてたもんね。
You had said so.
そうなんです。一緒に歌いたいな、いつかって言ってたのが今回こうやって夢が叶ってもうめちゃくちゃ嬉しいです。
That's right. I said I wanted to sing it together someday, and this time that dream came true, so I'm incredibly happy.
嬉しい！めちゃかっこよかった、ダンスも歌も。
I'm happy! You were so cool, both the dance and the song.
大人の色気、ちゃんと出せてましたか？
Was I able to show some adult sexiness?
出せてましたよ、大人の色気。
You showed it, adult sexiness.
やったー！嬉しい！
Yay! I'm happy!
出せてた色気。ちょっと不安？
The sexiness was there. A bit unsure?
やっぱり大人の色気ね、私たちね、見せていきましたから. いかがだったでしょうか？
As expected of adult sexiness, we showed it. How was it?
いかがだったでしょうか？何でちょっと引いてるんですか？
How was it? Why are you pulling back a bit?
いや嬉しい、本当にありがとうございます。
No, I'm happy, thank you so much.
まだ莉々華この後もあるので、ちょっともし良かったらお二人から頑張れのエールを貰いたいです！
Ririka still has more coming up, so if possible, I'd like to get words of encouragement from both of you!
あ、ソフトクリームも貰ったし、じゃあ二人でね、お礼のね、いたしましょう。
Ah, we got soft-serve too, so the two of us will give back in thanks.
お願いします！
Please!
じゃあ、せーので言うね。
Then, let's say it on "ready, set."
せーの、頑張れーーー！！！
Ready, set... DO YOUR BEST!!!
頑張りまーす！！！どこ行った？
I'll do my best!!! Where'd they go?
莉々華ー！莉々華ーー！
Ririka! Ririka!
Goin' goin' my way もうほっといて
Goin' goin' my way, just leave me alone
止めらんない熱 身任せて
I can't stop this heat, I'll let myself go
こりごりだ Rule は Break it down
I'm sick of the rules, break it down
我慢出来ない Let me free
I can't stand it, let me free
We are special でしょ？
We are special, right?
目が眩んでしまいそうな出立ちの My way
With an appearance that seems to dazzle, My way
In my mind
憧れてただけの Bad days
Just the bad days I longed for
今は何も響かない
Now nothing resonates
I know who I am, I...
ブランニューには勘弁
Give me a break from the 'brand new'
今は完全無視よ
I'm completely ignoring it now
何千万もありの Greedy style
Tens of millions of greedy styles
ださい足並みも興味ないの
I'm not interested in lame footsteps
ありのままでいたい
I want to stay as I am
Going my way
もう放っといて
Just leave me alone
止められない熱に任せて
Leaving it to the unstoppable heat
コリゴリだルールは
I'm fed up with rules
Break it down
我慢できない Let me free
I can't take it, let me be free
We are special
でしょう？ 揺るがないプライド
Right? An unwavering pride
それだけでいいの
That's all I need
足らればだらけの虚しい日々を
Those empty days full of 'what ifs'
Break it down, Break it...
...Break it down
We are special
誰に笑われても
No matter who laughs at me
私は歌うよ
I will sing
諦めばかりの世界など
In a world full of giving up
Break it down, Break it...
...進め
...Move forward
Break it down
Break it...
...進め
...Move forward
ハイテクなメイクやファッション
High-tech makeup and fashion
Self-love には変わらないよ
Don't change for self-love
体と心 誰のものでもないでしょ？
My body and soul don't belong to anyone, right?
いい加減いい大人だよね
We're good enough adults already
Inilah aku apa adanya
This is who I am as I am
Tidak sempurna tapi sepenuhnya diriku
Not perfect but fully myself
でも今は楽しいよ
But I'm having fun now
ありのままでいられるから
Because I can be as I am
Going my way
もう放っといて
Just leave me alone
止められない熱に任せて
Leaving it to the unstoppable heat
コリゴリだルールは
I'm fed up with rules
Break it down
我慢できない Let me free
I can't take it, let me be free
We are special
でしょう？ 揺るがないプライド
Right? An unwavering pride
それだけでいいの
That's all I need
足らればだらけの虚しい日々を
Those empty days full of 'what ifs'
Break it down, Break it...
...Break it down
We are special
誰に笑われても
No matter who laughs at me
私は歌うよ
I will sing
諦めばかりの世界など
In a world full of giving up
Break it down, Break it...
...進め
...Move forward
Can't break me down
Breaking me...
Break it down
Break it... 進め
Break it... Move forward
Break it down
Going my way
もう放っといて
Just leave me alone
止められない熱に任せて
Leaving it to the unstoppable heat
コリゴリだルールは
I'm fed up with rules
Break it down
我慢できない Let me free
I can't take it, let me be free
Break It Down
次の曲は！
The next song is!
SUPER DUPER!
Be the top, We are...
...ReGLOSS!
赤ん坊な子供のように
Like a baby child...
見てて！
...watch me!
SUPER DUPER
Yeah yeah, yeah yeah, yeah yeah, oh oh
目眩く 好奇心は羅針盤
A dazzling curiosity is my compass
行く末 神さえも知らぬ場所
A place where even God doesn't know the future
まじりっ気のない情熱が
Pure passion...
澄ました空虚を逆撫でしたとこ
...just brushed against the clear void
寝付きの悪い夜も
Even on sleepless nights
途方もないイロモノニュースも
And even with the absurd colorful news
目まぐるしい時代も全部
And all of this dizzying era
忘却の彼方へ笑い飛ばそう
Let's laugh it off into oblivion
Give me the, give me the beat right now!
SUPER DUPER
踊り狂うの シャングリラ
Dancing madly in Shangri-La
日が暮れるまで踊ろうよ
Let's dance until the sun goes down
誰が何と言おうと気にしない
I don't care what anyone says
見たかい？
Did you see it?
頂上までのシンボダケ
Just a milestone to the top
美しい声を響かせて
Letting a beautiful voice resonate
Yeah yeah, yeah yeah, yeah yeah, oh oh
俯いた世界を変えてみせよう
I'll show you I can change the downcast world
Yeah yeah, yeah yeah, yeah yeah
SUPER DUPER
根こそぎ奪い 真っ向から大逆転
Taking it all and a head-on great reversal
尊い一滴 決める 激アツ局面
A precious drop decides the super hot phase
転生してももう一度ここへ Comeback
Even if I reincarnate, I'll comeback here again
純正そのものがセンセーショナルな漫画
A purely sensational manga in itself
ビギナーから一躍 羽ばたいてオリジナル
From a beginner to a sudden flight, an original
一番手走らす 出待ち預けるジーニアス
Running first, a genius entrusted with the wait
巷を揺るがす Boy or Girl?
Shaking the town, Boy or Girl?
打ち出した答なら問題ない
If it's the answer I put out, no problem
煮えついた根底 飽きず病まないもの
A boiling foundation that never tires or sickens
疑うこともしらないまま
Still without even knowing how to doubt
そう言ってけ 覚悟は出来てるよ
Say that, I'm prepared
Give me the, give me the beat right now!
SUPER DUPER
踊り狂うの シャングリラ
Dancing madly in Shangri-La
日が暮れるまで踊ろうよ
Let's dance until the sun goes down
誰が何と言おうと気にしない
I don't care what anyone says
見たかい？
Did you see it?
リミッター解除
Limiter released
そう...
So...
SUPER DUPER
そっと貴方の静寂（しじま）だけ
Just gently in your silence...
美しい声を響かせて
I'll let my beautiful voice resonate
Yeah, yeah! Yeah, yeah! Ah-ah
俯いた世界を変えてみせよう
I'll show you I can change this downcast world
Yeah, yeah! Yeah, yeah!
SUPER DUPER
一喜一憂も
In every joy and sorrow
一言一句注いで
Pouring in every word and phrase
一心同体でいて
Being one in body and soul
こよなく恋したメロディと
With the melody I loved so dearly
敢えなく手放したレプリカ
And the replica I reluctantly let go
まもなく君との
Soon, with you...
境界線を越えリフレイン
I'll cross the boundary line and refrain
SUPER DUPER
オートクチュールのSHANGRI-LAで
In an haute couture SHANGRI-LA
日が暮れるまで踊ろうよ
Let's dance until the sun sets
誰が何と言おうと気にしない
I don't care what anyone says
リミッター解除
Limiter released
そう...
So...
SUPER DUPER
そっと貴方の静寂（しじま）だけ
Just gently in your silence...
美しい声を響かせて
I'll let my beautiful voice resonate
Yeah, yeah! Yeah, yeah! Ah-ah
俯いた世界を変えてみせよう
I'll show you I can change this downcast world
SUPER DUPER
というわけで、ReGLOSSで「SUPER DUPER」お送りしました！
And so, that was "SUPER DUPER" by ReGLOSS!
皆来てくれてありがとー！
Thank you everyone for coming!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
莉々ちゃんおめでとー！
Happy Birthday, Riri-chan!
さっきもやったんだけど、もう一回やってもいい？例の。
We did it earlier, but can we do it again? That thing.
あ、うん。いつもできます！
Oh, sure. We're always ready!
Reach the top, we are ReGLOSS!
せっかくだから、ちょっと皆に自己紹介して欲しくて。
Since we're here, I'd like everyone to introduce themselves.
じゃあ奏から！
Starting with Kanade!
はい！えーと、一条莉々華の恋人、音乃瀬奏です！
Yes! Um, I'm Otonose Kanade, Ichijo Ririka's lover!
俺？俺？いつの間に恋人だったんだ？
Me? Me? Since when were we lovers?
莉々華大好きだよー！
I love you, Ririka!
やったー！
Yay!
はい、一条莉々華にょ、ぺっちょ。轟はじめです。
Yes, Ichijo Ririka's pet. Todoroki Hajime here.
ぺ、ぺ、ぺ、ぺっちょ？
P-p-p-pet?
ワンワンワンワン！
Woof woof woof woof!
よしよしよしよし。
There, there.
そして！
And next!
一条莉々華の配信デスクのタンブラーを置くコースターみたいなやつ、儒烏風亭らでんです。
The coaster-like thing Ririka puts her tumbler on on her desk, I'm Juufuutei Raden.
何それは一体。
What on earth is that?
不気味や。不気味や。
How... creepy. So creepy.
不気味じゃない。
It's not creepy.
ずっと一緒。
Always together.
あ、そういうことか。
Oh, I see.
やったー！
Yay!
えー、皆来てくれてマジでありがとね。
Everyone, thank you so much for coming.
めっちゃ嬉しい。楽しかったー！
I'm so happy. That was fun!
誕生日だっけ？何の記念だっけ？
It's your birthday, right? What was the occasion again?
白々しいな。
Don't play dumb.
そうです！莉々華、大人になります！
That's right! Ririka is becoming an adult!
誕生日おめでとー！
Happy Birthday!
いやー、誕生日っていいな。毎日誕生日がいい。
Man, birthdays are great. I wish it was my birthday every day.
毎日、毎日年取ることになるけど。
You'd age every single day, though.
じゃあ、この話は終わりということで。
Alright, let's end this conversation then.
置いといてね。
Moving on.
はい。じゃあここからはね、ちょっと告知をさせて頂きたいなと思います！
Okay. So from here, I'd like to make some announcements!
こ、こ、告知！
A-a-announcements!
もしかして、一条莉々華誕生日記念2025グッズが出るってこと！？
Could it be that Ichijo Ririka's Birthday Celebration 2025 merchandise is coming out!?
じゃあ、こちらをご覧ください！ドン！
Then, please take a look at this! Boom!
一条莉々華 誕生日記念 2025
Ichijo Ririka Birthday Celebration 2025
これぞ莉々華！可愛いー！
That's our Ririka! So cute!
チュキチュキチュキチュキ！
Love it love it love it!
えー、こちらはね、初めての生誕祭のグッズということで盛りだくさんです！
This is my first birthday merch, so it's packed with items!
めっちゃいい！
It's so good!
イラストはトマリ先生に描いて頂きました！ありがとうございます！
The illustrations were done by Tomari-sensei! Thank you so much!
はー、可愛い！可愛くて美しくて最高だよね。
She's so cute! So cute and beautiful, it's the best.
じゃあ、ちょっと詳細も見ていきたいなと思います。
Now, let's take a look at the details.
まずはこちら！
First up is this!
イェイ！出た出た。皆画角に入ってね。
Yay! There it is. Everyone, get in the frame.
莉々華が大きすぎて写りきらない。
Ririka is too big, she's blocking the view.
アクリルスマホスタンド
Acrylic Smartphone Stand
オリジナル衣装で歌って踊ってる莉々華の描き下ろしイラスト...
A newly drawn illustration of Ririka singing and dancing in her original outfit...
して頂きました！もうめちゃくちゃ本当に可愛いし。
It's really, really cute.
スマホを上に置ける、つまりずっと一緒にいれるということ。イェーイ！
You can place your phone on top, which means we can be together forever. Yay!
配信！
Streams!
大事に使用してください。続いてはこちら！
Please use it with care. Next is this!
ランダムラバーストラップ
Random Rubber Strap
やっぱり莉々華オタクなので、自分自身も。
Well, I'm a Ririka otaku myself.
何しようかなって考えた時に、ラバスト欲しすぎ！と思って。
When I thought about what to make, I just really wanted a rubber strap!
欲しすぎ！
Really wanted it!
今回、上倉エク先生に4種類もの莉々華を書き下ろして頂きました！
This time, Kamikura Eku-sensei drew four different types of Ririka!
めっちゃ可愛い！ありがとうございます！
So cute! Thank you!
悪役令嬢なの？
Is that a villainess?
そうだよ、悪役令嬢の莉々華もいます！
That's right, there's a villainess Ririka too!
うわー！莉々様！莉々様！
Whoa! Lady Riri! Lady Riri!
莉々様だっけ？
Was it Lady Riri?
そう、莉々様。莉々様ですわ！
Yes, Lady Riri. I am Lady Riri!
ね、無理しました今。
Okay, I pushed myself a bit there.
で、こちらは、えーと、ランダムで1種類封入されております。
And this one, um, comes with one random type included.
おおー！ そして、続いてはこちら！
Ooh! And next up is this!
ジャン！ ウニペンケース！
Ta-da! Uni pen case!
えー、かわいいー！
Wow, so cute!
めっちゃ可愛いでしょ？ これめっちゃいい！
Isn't it super cute? This is great!
ふわふわでね、もうめちゃくちゃ可愛い。
It's fluffy and just incredibly cute.
お腹裂かれちゃってる？
Is its belly split open?
お腹です、背中、背中、背中！
It's the belly... no, back, back, back!
背中は裂いてますが、まあ内臓がペンみたいな感じでね。
The back is open, but the pens are like its insides.
なるほどなるほど。
I see, I see.
可愛がってあげてください。普段使いできるので、ぜひぜひ使ってください。
Please cherish it. It's for everyday use, so please use it.
かわいいー！ 続いてはこちら！
Cute! Moving on to the next item!
なんと、限界飯プレートが出まーす！
Believe it or not, the 'Genkai Meshi' Plate is coming out!
えー！ めっちゃ可愛い！ ご飯すごい！
Wow! So cute! The rice looks amazing!
そう、これね、あのお米が敷いてあるようなイラストのプレートなので、
Yeah, this plate has an illustration that looks like rice is spread out,
この上にね、おかずを乗せれば簡単にお手軽に限界飯が作れるという優れものになっております。
so if you put side dishes on top, you can easily make an 'extreme meal.'
え、めっちゃいいじゃん！ かわいい！
Eh, that's really cool! Cute!
そしてウニも、ちらっと書いてある。
And Uni is also peeking out there.
そう、ウニもいますよ。
Yes, Uni is there too.
ありがとう。じゃあ続いてはこちら！
Thank you. Now, next is this!
まあね、ボイスもやろうかなということで。
Well, I thought I'd do a voice set too.
今回、みんな待望のASMRボイス収録しております！
This time, I've recorded the long-awaited ASMR voice!
やったー！
Yay!
1個目は、「莉々華の部屋で一緒にゲーム」で、
The first one is 'Playing games together in Ririka's room.'
まあ莉々華のね、おうちで、隣でなんか一緒にゲームをしてるかのような
It's a lovey-dovey voice set where it's like we're
ラブラブボイスとなっておりますので、よろしくお願いします。
playing games together at my place, so please look forward to it.
いいねー！ 買うしかない！
Nice! Gotta buy it!
そしてなんとですね、フルセットの購入特典もございます。
And surprisingly, there are also benefits for purchasing the full set.
こちらです、ジャン！
Here they are, ta-da!
はい、まずは、直筆サインがついてきます！
First, it comes with a handwritten autograph!
で、こちらはですね、もう莉々華限定とかじゃなくて、
And for this, instead of making it limited,
買ってくださった方には全員におつけしたいと思っているので、ぜひいっぱい購入してもらえると嬉しいです。
I want to give it to everyone who buys it, so I'd be happy if lots of you got one.
ポストカードに直筆サインをつけて、お渡しします。
I'll be giving them out as postcards with handwritten autographs.
で、もう一つが、さっきASMR1個目はって言ったんですけど、
And the other thing, I mentioned the first ASMR earlier,
2つ目がこちらで、「あなたの誕生日をお祝い」ということで。
the second one is 'Celebrating your birthday.'
今日は莉々華の誕生日をみんなにこうやってお祝いしてもらってるわけですけど、
Today, everyone is celebrating my birthday like this,
莉々華もみんなの誕生日をお祝いしたいと思って、今回準備しました。
but I wanted to celebrate your birthdays too, so I prepared this.
ぜひ自分の誕生日に聞いてください。
Please listen to it on your own birthday.
はい、じゃあ改めてフルセットはこちらとなります。
Okay, so once again, here is the full set.
ジャーン！ いや、なんて豪華なんだ！
Ta-da! Wow, how luxurious!
あまりにいっぱいありすぎて、絶対に買ってください。絶対に絶対に。よろしくお願いします。
There's so much in it, so please, please buy it. Absolutely. Thank you!
そしてさらに、タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として、
Furthermore, as a full set benefit for the Talent Premium Goods,
ホロライブOFFICIAL CARD GAMEでなんと使用できるカードが1枚ついてきます！
you get one card that can be used in the Hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME!
カードはホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップで購入された方のみが対象となります。
The card is only for those who purchase from the Hololive Production Official Shop.
特典につくのは推しをアピールできる「推しホロメン」のカードです。
The bonus is an 'Oshi Holomen' card to show off your favorite.
カードの詳細や遊び方などについてはホームページにてご確認ください。
Please check the website for details on the card and how to play.
なんと！ 実はまだお知らせがあるんです。
Wait! Actually, there's more news.
こちらをご覧ください。デーーン！
Please look at this. Ta-da!
おー、出た！ よしよしよし。
Oh, there it is! Nice, nice, nice.
一条莉々華のLINEスタンプの制作が決定しましたーー！！
The production of Ichijou Ririka LINE stamps has been confirmed!!
詳細はね、後日公開となりますので、ご確認のほど、よろしくお願いします。
Details will be released at a later date, so please look forward to it.
めっちゃ可愛くない？ やばすぎでしょ。いっぱい使ってください。
Aren't they so cute? They're amazing. Please use them a lot.
以上、一条莉々華生誕祭記念ライブのグッズ情報でした。
That's all for the merchandise information for Ichijou Ririka's Birthday Celebration Live.
みんな買っていただけるととても嬉しいです。
I'd be very happy if everyone could buy them.
生誕ライブ、無事やることができて、もうめちゃくちゃ嬉しい気持ちでいっぱいです。
I'm just so full of happiness that I was able to successfully hold this birthday live.
たくさんの応援コメント、もう常日頃からね、莉々華にいっぱい届いております。
Lots of supportive comments reach me every single day.
みんなが応援してくれたおかげで、また莉々華ダンス頑張れた、歌も頑張れた。
Thanks to everyone's support, I was able to work hard on my dancing and singing.
これからもたくさんたくさん、みんなといろんな景色見れるように頑張ります。
I'll keep working hard so I can see many more sights with everyone.
ReGLOSS、どこ行った？ 消えた？
Where did ReGLOSS go? Did they disappear?
え、なんで？ どこー？
Eh, why? Where are you?
莉々、こっちだよー！ こっちこっち！
Riri, we're over here! Over here!
え、あんなところに。メリーゴーランドに乗ってたんだ。
Eh, over there. They were on the carousel.
あはは、楽しそう。
Ahaha, they look like they're having fun.
白馬の王子様みたいになってるじゃん、番長。
You look like a prince on a white horse, Bancho.
だろだろ。パカラパカラ。
Right? Clip-clop, clip-clop.
いいなあ。莉々華も乗りたい気持ちはいっぱいあるんだけどさ、
Must be nice. I really want to ride it too, but...
この後まだアンコールライブもあるから。
we still have the encore live coming up.
ごめん、これ3人用なんだ。
Sorry, this is for three people.
いやいやいや、こんなに席あったのに、3人用だったんだこれ。
No, no, no, there were so many seats, but it's only for three people?
そうなの。4人乗ると止まっちゃう。重さで。莉々華の。
That's right. It'll stop if four people ride it. Because of Ririka's... weight.
莉々華の体重のせいで。
Because of Ririka's weight?!
まあなんか言ってますけれどね。
Well, they're saying things, but...
この後、莉々華、万全でアンコールライブがあります！
after this, I'll be in top form for the encore live!
おー、頑張れー！
Oh, good luck!
アンコールライブでは、ホロライブのあの曲やあの曲を歌っちゃいまーす！
In the encore live, I'll be singing those Hololive songs!
…と思って、思ってるので、楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです！
...so I hope you all enjoy it!
楽しんでー！イエーイ！
Enjoy! Yay!
じゃあみんな、今日来てくれて本当ありがとね！
So everyone, thank you so much for coming today!
このあともゆっくり楽しんでね！バイバイ！
Keep enjoying the rest of the show! Bye-bye!
バイバーイ！ありがとー！
Bye-bye! Thank you!